Guide to the Western Wood Products Association Records 1909-1970
Oregon Historical Society, Research Library
- West Coast Lumbermen's Association Records, 1909-1970; Subgroup 1; 60 linear ft. (40 document cases; 28 record cartons; 3 boxes Oversize A—11x14; 6 boxes Oversize B-1—16x20)
  - Governance and Membership Records, 1911-1970; Series A
    - Government and Industry Relations, 1915-1965; 1915-1936; Subseries 10
      - Central Committee on Lumber Standards and Chairman of Consulting Committee—joint meeting report, 1923 (Box-folder 15/4)
      - Central Committee on Lumber Standards—proposed American lumber standards, 1923 (Box-folder 15/5)
      - Consulting Committee on Lumber Standards—meeting reports, 1923 (Box-folder 15/6-7)
      - Consulting Committee on Lumber Standards—recommendations, 1923 (Box-folder 15/8)
      - Federal Housing Administration (FHA)— insurance and loan information and amendments to the National Housing Act, 1954-1958 (Box-folder 15/9)
      - Federal Trade Commission—correspondence, 1915-1916; 1919-1920 (Box-folder 15/10)
      - General Standardization Conference on Lumber—minutes, 1923 (Box-folder 15/11)
      - WCLA Grades—clippings, meeting information, press releases, and reports, 1956; 1962-1965 (Box-folder 16/1)
      - WCLA Grade Standardization Report, Nos. 1-23, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 16/2)
      - Lumber Industry Merchandising Council—minutes, 1963 (Box-folder 16/3)
      - Lumber Manufacturers Standardization Committee—meeting report, 1923 (Box-folder 16/4)
      - National Lumber Manufacturers Association Lumber Standards—meeting reports, 1922 (Box-folder 16/5)
      - NRA Lumber Code—article and report, 1934-1935; 1959 (Box-folder 16/6)
      - NRA Lumber Code— West Coast Lumber Code Bulletin, 1933-1935 (Box 68)
        The bulletins in Box 68 have been bound into a volume.
      - Oregon Unemployment Compensation Commission—minutes, 1936 (Box-folder 16/7)
      - U.S. Forest Products Laboratory—report on grade specifications for yard lumber, 1923 (Box-folder 16/8)
      - U.S. Forest Products Laboratory—report on development of specifications for yard lumber, circa 1925 (Box-folder 16/9)
      - U.S. Forest Products Laboratory—grading rules and working stresses for structural timbers, circa 1925 (Box-folder 16/10)
      - West Coast Car Material: Its Manufacture and Use—industry meeting report, 1930 (Box-folder 16/11)
      - West Coast Forest Products Bureau, Trustees and Finance Committee—minutes, 1922 (Box-folder 16/12)
      - WCLA Import-Export Committee, Pacific Lumber Exporters Association and Pacific Coast European Conference—minutes, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 16/13)
    - Member Relations, 1911-1928; 1943-1964; Subseries 11
      Includes stock certificates, membership literature, and materials about forestry and general taxation issues facing the Pacific Northwest lumber industry.
      - Capital Stock Certificates [in bound volumes], 1911-1928; 1952-1958; 1958-1960 (Box 74, Box 75, Box 76)
      - Membership Drives, 1944; 1947; 1950 (Box-folder 16/14)
      - Member Solicitation Literature, 1950; 1952 (Box-folder 16/15)
      - Forestry and General Taxation—articles, circulars, correspondence, pamphlets, reports, and a booklet, A Study of Forest Taxation in the Pacific Northwest, 1943-1945; 1952-1955; 1959-1961; 1964 (Box-folder 16/16, Box-folder 17/1)
    - Committees, 1928-1964; Subseries 12
      The majority of the subseries consists of meeting minutes and correspondence.
      - Activities Survey Special Committee—correspondence, 1960 (Box-folder 17/2)
      - Advertising and Promotion Committee—addresses, article, circulars, correspondence, minutes, and radio spots, 1960-1964 (Box-folder 17/3-7)
      - Special Advertising Committees—minutes, 1945-1949 (Box-folder 17/8-9)
      - Carloading and Packaging Committee—minutes, 1963 (Box-folder 17/10)
      - Cedar and Hemlock Committees—minutes, 1930-1932; 1935-1939 (Box-folder 17/11)
      - Clearing, Mobilization, War and National Defense Committees—minutes, 1940-1944; 1951 (Box-folder 17/12)
      - Douglas Fir Advisory Committee to Office of Price Administration, Stone Advisory Committee (OPA), Price List Committee, Atlantic Coast Subcommittee, and Trade Practice Committee—minutes, 1939-1943 (Box-folder 17/13)
      - Douglas Fir, Sitka Spruce, and Western Red Cedar Advisory Committees to Office of Price Administration—minutes, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 18/1)
      - Dues Structure Committee—minutes, 1963 (Box-folder 18/2)
      - Executive Committee—minutes, circulars and correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 18/3-4)
      - Joint Committee on Forest Conservation, WCLA and Pacific Northwest Loggers Association—minutes, 1934-1945; 1952 (Box-folder 18/5-6)
      - General Maritime and Cargo Committees—minutes and report, 1930-1931; 1936-1942; 1944-1945; 1948-1949; 1951-1952; 1963 (Box-folder 18/7)
      - Grades and Inspection and Grading Rules Committees—minutes, 1932-1933; 1935-1940 (Box-folder 18/8)
      - Grading Rules, Contact, Sales Managers, Grades and Manufacture, and Grades and Inspection Advisory Committees—minutes, 1928-1932; 1937; 1939-1940 (Box-folder 18/9)
      - Import-Export Committee—minutes, 1950; 1962 (Box-folder 19/1)
      - Industrial Facts Committee, Information Department overview, Manufacturers-Wholesalers Joint Committee and Logging Committee—minutes, 1929-1931; 1935 (Box-folder 19/2)
      - Insurance Committee—activities and minutes, 1963 (Box-folder 19/3)
      - Legislative Committee, Oregon Unemployment Compensation Commission and Economics Committee—minutes, 1936-1939; 1947 (Box-folder 19/4)
      - Liaison Committee, WCLA and WPA—correspondence, minutes and report, 1959-1964 (Box-folder 19/5-9)
      - Atlantic Coast Price List Subcommittee, Joint List Committee, Trade Practice Committee Subcommittee, California List Committee, and Rail "C" List Committee—minutes, 1930; 1932; 1939 (Box-folder 19/10)
      - Lumber Costs and Reports Committee—minutes, 1933-1935; 1937-1940; 1942; 1944; 1948-1951; 1959; 1961; 1964 (Box-folder 19/11-14)
      - Manufacture Committee, Millwork Committee, Moulding Committee, National Lumber Manufacturers Credit Corporation, Sitka Spruce Division, and Contact Committee—minutes, 1929-1931; 1934; 1937-1938 (Box-folder 20/1)
      - Joint Committee of Manufacturers and Retailers—correspondence and minutes, 1945; 1948; 1959 (Box-folder 20/2)
      - NRA Lumber Code, Committee on Control of Lumber Production—minutes, 1933-1935 (Box-folder 20/3-5)
      - NRA Lumber Code Committees and NRA Industry Meetings—minutes, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 20/6)
        Folder 20/6 contains minutes from the following committees and industry meetings: District Meetings, Special Committee on Differentials, Inter-species Correlating Committee, Spruce Manufacturers, Battery Separator Manufacturers, Douglas Fir Subdivision of Pole and Piling Division, Lumber Code Agencies Joint Meetings, and General Meeting of the West Coast Lumber Industry.
      - NRA Lumber Code, Joint Committee on Labor—minutes, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 20/7-8)
      - NRA Lumber Code, Minimum Prices and Trade Practices Committee—minutes, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 20/9, Box-folder 21/1)
      - NRA Lumber Code, Trade Complaints Committee—minutes, 1934 (Box-folder 21/2)
      - Nominating Committee—minutes, 1964 (Box-folder 21/3)
      - Open Car Loading Rules Committee—minutes, 1942; 1945-1947; 1952 (Box-folder 21/4)
      - Price List, Trade Practice and Firm Price List Committees—minutes, 1929-1931; 1935; 1937-1940 (Box-folder 21/5)
      - Public Relations Committee and Research and Technical Committee—minutes, 1941-1949 (Box-folder 21/6-7)
      - Railroad, Car Builders and Lumber Industry (WCLA special meeting)—minutes, 1930 (Box-folder 21/8)
      - WCLA Reorganization Committee—minutes, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 21/9)
      - Standing Committees—correspondence and member lists, 1955-1962 (Box-folder 21/10, Box-folder 22/1-4)
      - Tariffs and Reciprocal Trade Negotiations, Governmental Relations, Dues and Budget, and Deliquent Accounts Committees—minutes, 1935-1942; 1945-1946; 1948-1949 (Box-folder 22/5)
      - Technical Committee—correspondence, 1964 (Box-folder 22/6)
      - Trade Promotion/Extension Committee—minutes, 1929-1930; 1935-1951; 1964 (Box-folder 22/7-8, Box-folder 23/1-4)
      - Trade Promotion Coordinating Committee—minutes, 1949 (Box-folder 23/5)
      - Traffic Committee—minutes, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 23/6)
      - Treasurer's Committee—minutes, 1964 (Box-folder 23/7)
      - Wood Siding Committee and Research and Technical Committee—minutes, 1951 (Box-folder 23/8)
  - Departments and Functions, 1909-1967; Series B
    The series is arranged into seven subseries based on the activities and departmental organization of the West Coast Lumbermen's Association.
    - Accounting Service, 1950; 1958; Subseries 1
      - WCLA Uniform Accounting System, 1950; 1958 (Box-folder 23/9-10)
    - Educational Program Department, 1941-1964; Subseries 2
      The subseries contains descriptions of educational activities and samples of literature and other promotional materials developed by the WCLA for students.
      - Educational Activities, 1945; 1949; 1960 (Box-folder 23/11)
        Includes correspondence and descriptions of the WCLA's educational activities, including the distribution of filmstrips, motion pictures, literature, and involvement in conservation and outdoor education workshops.
      - Educational Literature, 1941-1942; 1944-1946; 1949; 1951-1955; 1957-1958; 1960-1962 (Box-folder 23/12-13)
        Includes samples of educational literature, brochures and promotional materials. Folder 23/13 contains teaching handbooks for students and A Manual of Junior Forestry for Washington and Oregon.
      - Education—promotion for visual aids, 1944; 1946; 1948-1949; 1950; 1952-1953; 1955; 1958; 1964 (Box-folder 24/1)
      - Sawdust Trails: A Student's Digest of Logging and Lumber Manufacturing in the Douglas Fir Region, 1944; 1946-1949 (Box-folder 24/2)
        The folder contains publication information about Sawdust Trails and samples of other promotional booklets developed for students.
    - Lumber Promotion Department, 1926-1964; Subseries 3
      - Trade Promotion—advertisements and correspondence, 1929; 1942-1947; 1949-1950; 1953; 1956; 1958 (Box-folder 24/3)
      - Advertisements—numbered, 1960-1964 (Box-folder 24/4-18)
      - Advertising and Historical Information, 1935; 1940; 1963 (Box-folder 24/19)
        Includes a description of the Western Homes Foundation, an organization established by the WCLA and other trade assocations to promote the construction of homes for the mass market. Also includes a flyer and background information about storage facilities for boats and boat trailers.
      - Cedar, Western Red—contract, marketing study and promotional materials, 1951-1955 (Box-folder 25/1)
      - Commercial Buildings, Churches and Other Structures—promotional booklets, 1959-1962 (Box-folder 25/2)
      - Trade Promotion—correspondence, 1937-1940 (Box-folder 25/3)
      - Do-It-Yourself Plans, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 25/4)
      - Douglas Fir—promotional materials, 1937; circa 1940; 1950 (Box-folder 25/5)
      - Farm Books and Pamphlets, 1928; 1940-1942; 1944; 1951; circa 1955; 1956 (Box-folder 25/6)
      - WCLA Grades—circulars, a grade guide, press releases and reports, 1944-1949; 1955-1960 (Box-folder 25/7)
      - WCLA Grades in Home Construction—pamphlets, 1945; 1960-1961 (Box-folder 25/8)
      - Hemlock, West Coast—correspondence, 1937; 1939 (Box-folder 25/9)
      - Hemlock, West Coast—promotional materials, 1943; 1951; 1956; 1963 (Box-folder 25/10)
      - Home Construction—advertisements, 1931-1932; 1934; 1936-1941 (Box 77)
        A scrapbook containing samples of advertisements from the WCLA's promotional campaigns during the Great Depression.
      - Home Construction—promotional materials, 1929; 1942; 1945; 1948; circa 1955; 1961 (Box-folder 25/11)
      - Membership Directories— Where to Buy West Coast Lumber, 1942; 1945-1951; 1956-1964 (Box-folder 26/1-2)
      - Promotional Materials—advertisements, booklets and flyers produced by the WCLA to promote various types of West Coast lumber, 1926-1929; circa 1931; 1933; 1936; 1939-1942; 1944-1947; 1949-1956; 1958-1964 (Box-folder 26/3-8)
      - Sample Advertisements, 1948-1949; 1957 (Box-folder 26/9)
      - School Buildings—wood construction, 1949-1950; 1952; 1955; 1958; 1961-1963 (Box-folder 27/1)
      - Sitka Spruce—correspondence, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 27/2)
      - Sitka Spruce—promotional materials, 1940; circa 1950 (Box-folder 27/3)
      - Sitka Spruce Statistical Reports and Barometer—correspondence, 1935; 1937-1940 (Box-folder 27/4)
    - Public Relations Department, 1919-1965; Subseries 4
      Among the topics covered are conservation; forest fires, forestry, forest resources, and foreign trade missions.
      - Companies with "Longest Life Span"—correspondence, 1949; 1951 (Box-folder 27/5)
      - Conservation—forestry and general, 1944-1945; 1948-1953; 1955; 1957; 1963-1964 (Box-folder 27/6)
      - Crow's Lumber Digest—special WCLA issues, 1957-1960; 1963 (Box-folder 27/7)
      - A Decade of Progress in Douglas Fir, Forestry—publication, 1943 (Box-folder 27/8)
      - Forest Fires, 1943; 1945; 1949; 1951-1952; 1957 (Box-folder 27/9)
      - Forest Practice Handbook—publication, 1937 (Box-folder 27/10)
      - Forest Resources of the Douglas Fir Region—publication, 1946 (Box-folder 27/11)
      - Forestry—publicity, 1946-1947; 1950 (Box-folder 27/12)
      - Forestry History—publicity, 1944; 1946; 1948-1952; 1954-1955; 1964 (Box-folder 27/13)
      - Forestry Research—publicity, 1948; 1951; 1954 (Box-folder 27/14)
      - Forest Resources—publicity and reports, 1940; 1942-1944; 1946; 1951-1952; 1965 (Box-folder 27/15)
      - Head Rig—borrowed reference correspondence, 1951; 1964-1966 (Box-folder 28/1)
      - Head Rig—letter and phone responses to book, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 28/2-4)
      - Head Rig—mailing lists, circa 1965; 1965-1966 (Box-folder 28/5-7)
      - Kendall, Paul E., Advertising Manager—correspondence, 1946; 1950-1951 (Box-folder 28/8)
      - More Timber—publication, 1947 (Box-folder 28/9)
      - Motion Picture Lecture Script for Film No. 06879— Green Harvest, circa 1955 (Box-folder 28/10)
      - Issues of Out of the Woods by James Stevens, Public Relations Counsel, 1943-circa 1945; circa 1945-1957 (Box 59, Box 60)
        The materials contained in Boxes 59 and 60 have been bound into volumes.
      - Priaulx, Arthur W., Public Relations Director—correspondence, 1943-1945; 1949; 1951 (Box-folder 28/11)
      - Public Relations Literature, 1919; 1930; 1937; 1943-1946; circa 1950; 1953 (Box-folder 28/12)
      - Roberts, A. K., Visual Education Director—correspondence, 1944-1946; 1949 (Box-folder 28/13)
      - Scrapbooks—newspaper clippings, 1945; 1937; 1941-1943; 1949 (Box 74, Box 76)
      - Simpson, Harold V., Executive Vice President—addresses, articles, correspondence, news clippings, and press releases, 1942; 1945-1952; 1961-1962 (Box-folder 29/1-3)
      - Stevens, James, Public Relations Counsel—correspondence, 1942-1957 (Box-folder 29/4-9, Box-folder 30/1-6)
      - Stevens, James, Public Relations Counsel—correspondence and issues of Out of the Woods, 1945-1950 (Box-folder 30/7)
      - Stevens, James, Public Relations Counsel—partial manuscript, The Lumber Business, and issues of Out of the Woods, 1946; circa 1953; 1954-1957 (Box-folder 31/1-2)
      - Summary report of foreign trade missions—"Principal Export Markets for Western Lumber", circa 1965 (Box-folder 31/3)
      - Trade Missions to Australia and Japan, 1965 (Box-folder 31/4)
      - Trade Mission to Europe, 1963 (Box-folder 31/5)
      - Trade Mission to Japan, 1965 (Box-folder 31/6)
      - Tree Farms, Montesano, Wash., Tenth Anniversary Celebration—correspondence, 1928; 1947-1949; 1951 (Box-folder 31/7)
        Commemorated the establishment of the first tree farm in the state of Washington in 1941.
    - Statistical Department, 1916-1967; Subseries 5
      The subseries contains lumber industry and related reports produced by the WCLA and other trade associations for their members, the press and other interested parties. The materials contained in Boxes 60-68 and 77 have been bound into volumes.
      - Barometer issues—WCLA, Southern Pine Association, Western Pine Manufacturers Association, and National Lumber Manufacturers Association, 1916-1917; 1918-1927; 1928-1932; 1933-1935 (Box 60, Box 61, Box 62, Box 63)
      - Barometer and Industrial Facts issues—WCLA and National Lumber Manufacturers Association, 1936-1939; 1940-1947; 1948-1956; 1957-1960 (Box 63, Box 64, Box 65, Box 66)
      - WCLA Industrial Facts issues, 1961-1963 (Box 66)
      - Barometer Distribution, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 31/8)
      - Barometer—distribution policy and revision, 1939; 1941 (Box-folder 31/9)
      - Analysis of Douglas Fir Costs and Sales Returns, 1918-1931 (Box 66)
      - Analysis of Douglas Fir and West Coast Hemlock Logs, 1917-1918; 1933-1934 (Box-folder 32/1)
      - Analysis of Invoices—blank forms, 1940 (Box-folder 32/2)
      - Average Price Received, 1935-1945 (Box 67)
      - Average Realization on Lumber Shipments, 1946-1954 (Box 67)
      - Cost and Realization Reports, 1934-1945 (Box 67)
      - Davis Sales Service—volume and average, actual sales direct and wholesale of various lumber companies, 1926-1927 (Box 77)
      - Employment Statistics, 1933-1954 (Box 67)
      - Export Waterborne Shipments—WCLA and Pacific Lumber Inspection Bureau, 1949-1954 (Box 68)
      - Injury Frequency Information—monthly reports, 1957-1960; 1954-1957 (Box 67, Box 68)
      - Log Analysis of Lumber Orders Accepted, 1933-1935 (Box 60)
      - Lumber Industry—statistical surveys of lumber production and other statistical information, 1927; 1935; 1938; 1944; 1946-1948; circa 1955; 1963 (Box-folder 32/3)
      - Reports of Costs and Sales Returns for NRA Period, 1933-1934 (Box 66)
      - Weekly Sales Bulletins, 1923-1926 (Box 60)
      - Sawmill Operations of the Douglas Fir Region—monthly and quarterly reports, 1948-1954 (Box 67)
      - Statistical Literature, 1929; 1935; 1938 (Box-folder 32/4)
      - Statistical and Merchandising Service Plan and Estimated Shipping Weights, 1927; 1929-1930; 1939-1940 (Box-folder 32/5)
      - WCLA and WWPA Statistical Year Book, 1948; 1951-1962; 1964-1965; 1967 (Box-folder 32/6-14)
      - West Coast Lumber Facts—publication, 1937; 1941 (Box-folder 33/1-2)
    - Technical Service Department, 1922-1966; Subseries 6
      Contains lumber grading rules information and construction specifications.
      - WCLA, WCLIB and WWPA Grading Rules and Grade Use Guides, 1922; 1926; 1929; 1934; 1940; 1944; 1956; 1960; 1962; 1965-1966 (Box-folder 33/3-4)
      - Heavy Construction, 1937; 1939-1945; 1956-1957; 1964 (Box-folder 33/5)
      - Highway Structures and Bridges, 1941; 1945; 1948; 1952; 1954-1955 (Box-folder 33/6)
      - Lumber Technical and Seasoning Data, 1942 (Box-folder 33/7)
      - May, T. K., Director, Technical Service Department—lumber standards and specifications, 1930; 1945; 1952-1955; 1959; 1961-1963 (Box-folder 33/8)
      - Paint Literature, 1939; circa 1950 (Box-folder 33/9)
      - Research Bulletins—lumber seasoning and chemical treatments, 1927; 1942-1946; 1955 (Box-folder 33/10)
      - Structural Glued Laminated Lumber—specifications, 1945; 1951-1952; 1955; 1958-1959; 1960; 1963 (Box-folder 33/11)
      - Timber Structures, 1943; circa 1945; 1947 (Box-folder 34/1)
    - Traffic Department, 1909-1965; Subseries 7
      Contains materials concerning the transport of lumber via rail and ship, including differential price lists and rate books. Also includes information about traffic problems, such as freight car shortages, as well as Canadian import issues.
      - Atlantic Coast Differentials for Douglas Fir and West Coast Hemlock, 1935 (Box-folder 34/2)
      - Articles, correspondence, newsletters and petition before Interstate Commerce Commission, 1921; 1931; 1945-1949; 1961 (Box-folder 34/3)
      - Differential Price Lists, 1909; 1911; 1917; 1919; 1922; 1926-1927; 1939-1940 (Box-folder 34/4)
      - Foreign Trade, 1919; 1923; 1935; 1938-1939; 1945-1948; 1953-1954 (Box-folder 34/5)
      - Freight Car Shortage, 1946-1948; 1950-1952; 1955; 1960; 1963-1965 (Box-folder 34/6)
      - Imports, Canadian Forest Products—exhibits, press releases, statements and statistics, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 34/7-9)
      - Loading Rules, Rate Maps and Rate Tables, 1943; 1946-1949; 1951-1952; 1954; 1956-1961 (Box-folder 35/1)
      - News Releases, Progress Reports and Vice President Reports, 1947; 1949; 1951-1953; 1955-1965 (Box-folder 35/2)
      - "A Quarter Century Record for WCLA Traffic Department"—report, 1963 (Box-folder 35/3)
      - Rate Book, 1926-1929 (Box-folder 35/4-5)
      - Water Rates, 1936; 1946-1948; 1950; 1952-1953; 1956-1957; 1961-1963; 1965 (Box-folder 35/6)
  - Branches and Associated Organizations, 1911-1965; Series C
    The series is arranged into three subseries based on the various branches and associated organizations of the West Coast Lumbermen's Association. Subseries 1 and 2 contain some records of the West Coast Lumber Inspection Bureau and the Western Pine Association. Subseries 3 contains some records of other organizations.
    - West Coast Lumber Inspection Bureau (WCLIB) Records, circa 1945-1964; Subseries 1
      - Annual Reports, 1954-1955; 1957-1963 (Box-folder 35/7-15)
      - Applications and Agreements—blank forms, circa 1945-1955 (Box-folder 36/1)
      - Clear Grades Subcommittee—minutes, 1963 (Box-folder 36/2)
      - District Meetings—lists of companies, individuals and reservation information, 1964 (Box-folder 36/3)
      - Executive Committee—minutes, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 36/4-5)
      - Grading Rules Committee—minutes, 1963 (Box-folder 36/6)
      - Joint Negotiating Committee—minutes, 1963 (Box-folder 36/7)
      - Office of Price Stabilization—California, Oregon and Washington State service charge increase, 1952 (Box-folder 36/8-9)
      - Office of Price Stabilization—application for service charge increase in Oregon and Washington State, 1952 (Box-folder 36/10)
    - Western Pine Associaton (WPA) Records, 1931-1965; Subseries 2
      - Account Journals, 1931-1955; 1965-1966 (Box 76)
      - Activities Reports, 1936; 1938-1963 (Box-folder 36/11-12, Box-folder 37/1)
      - Annual Members' Meeting—minutes, 1961; 1963 (Box-folder 37/2-3)
      - Board of Directors—correspondence and minutes, 1960-1963 (Box-folder 37/4-8)
      - WPA and WWPA Financial Statements, 1933-1935; 1963-1965 (Box-folder 37/9-12)
      - WPA-WCLIB Meeting—minutes, 1962 (Box-folder 37/13)
    - Records from Various Organizations, 1911-1963; Subseries 3
      - Forest Conservation Committee of Pacific Northwest Forest Industries—historical background and plan of organization, 1949 (Box-folder 37/14)
      - Forest Conservation Committee of Pacific Northwest Forest Industries/Joint Committee on Forest Conservation—minutes, 1946-1950 (Box-folder 37/15)
      - Forest Conservation Committee of Pacific Northwest Forest Industries—minutes, 1934; 1950-1952 (Box-folder 38/1-2)
      - Forest Industries Information Committee—correspondence, information booklets and paper and pulp industry statistics by state, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 38/3-4)
      - Forest Industries Information Committee—listings of officers, mills, and members of U.S. Congress by state, circa 1944 (Box-folder 38/5)
      - Industrial Forestry Association (IFA)—annual forest products statistics for Oregon and Washington State, 1951-1954; 1956-1957; 1959-1962 (Box-folder 38/6)
      - Lumber Code Authority Bulletin—NRA Code, 1933-1935 (Box 68)
        The bulletins contained in Box 68 have been bound into volumes.